Okay, so here we are, back in Jupyter Lab, ready for the next use of a frontier model, and see this
다시 주피터 연구실입니다 프런티어 모델을 사용할 준비가 됐어요 전문 지식을
now as somewhere where you're really building expertise.
구축하는 곳으로 보고 싶네요
This should be very natural to you.
아주 자연스러울 거예요
As usual, we start by considering our system prompt and being thoughtful about how we will prompt the
늘 그렇듯 시스템 프롬프트와 모델을 어떻게 프롬프트할지 심사숙고하며 시작하죠
Um, what we're going to say to to the model is, look, you identify and summarize the five most detailed
모델에게 하는 말은 목록에서 가장 자세한 5가지 항목을 골라 요약하라는
items from a list by selecting deals that have the most detailed, high quality descriptions and the
겁니다 가장 자세하고, 잘 묘사되고 가장 확실한 가격이 있는 걸 선택해서요
most clear price, uh, respond strictly in JSON, blah, blah, blah.
JSON에 대응하세요
Um, most important is you respond with five deals that have the most detailed product description.
가장 중요한 건 5건의 거래에 가장 자세한 제품 설명이 있는 거예요
It's not important to mention the terms.
조건은 중요하지 않아요
Um, and now I also I have laid out here the JSON structure.
그리고 여기 JSON 구조도 배치해뒀어요
I should probably mention that this isn't required because we're going to be using structured outputs,
꼭 필요한 것은 아니라는 것을 말씀드리고 싶네요. 구조화된 출력물들을
but I like to do this to use it as another opportunity to give more direction on exactly what's expected
사용할 것이기 때문입니다. 하지만 저는 이것을 또 다른 기회로 사용하고 싶습니다. 각각의 것에 대해 더 많은 방향을 제시할 수
in each one.
있도록요.
Uh, so this is something which you can experiment with.
실험해 볼 수 있는 거예요
But strictly speaking we shouldn't need to specify JSON like that.
엄밀히 말하면 JSON을 그렇게 지정할 필요는 없어요
So that's my system prompt.
그게 제 시스템 프롬프트예요
The user prompt says respond with the most promising five deals from this list.
사용자 프롬프트는 이 목록에서 가장 유망한 거래 5건에 응답하라고 하죠
Selecting those.
그걸 선택하는 거죠
Blah blah blah blah blah.
어쩌고저쩌고 말이죠
I will let you read it through.
읽어 보게 해 줄게요
But you know, this kind of stuff.
하지만 이런 건 잘 아시죠
Well, uh, and um, uh, the deals and then it lists the deals and it calls deal dot describe for each
딜을 적고 나열한 다음 딜닷컴을 호출해요 각각에 대해서요
Okay.
네
That's simple.
간단해요
So now let me just print the beginning of the user prompt is quite long.
사용자 프롬프트의 시작을 프린트하겠습니다 꽤 길군요
So I'm just going to print the first 2000 characters of the user prompt.
사용자 프롬프트의 처음 2천 글자를 프린트할게요
So you get a sense for it.
Get it 하면 감이 오죠
Here it is.
여기 있네요
Let's have a look.
한번 보죠
So there's the uh user prompt respond with blah blah blah blah blah blah blah.
사용자 프롬프트 응답에 어쩌고저쩌고 라음이 있네요
And then here are the deals.
그럼 이렇게 하죠
And this is the description that we've taken from um, the, the, the description function that we
이게 설명이에요 설명 메서드 전에 봤던 설명 함수에서
looked at before the describe method.
가져온 거죠
So essentially the task that we're assigning to GPT four is to digest this list of deals, select pluck
본질적으로 GPT 4에 할당하는 작업은 이 목록의 거래를 파악하는 겁니다 목록에서 선택 선택하기
out from this list and there's going to be 50 of them.
50개가 될 거예요
Pick the five which have the clearest description and from which it can take the price.
가장 명확한 묘사와 가격을 나타내는 5개를 고르세요
Parse the price out of this in a way that is that is most clear.
가장 명확한 방식으로 가격을 분석하세요
And that is, of course, a fuzzy kind of problem that requires some thought.
물론 그런 건 좀 모호한 문제라 생각을 해야 하죠
It's the kind of thing that would be only a year or two ago would have been unthinkably hard.
1, 2년 전이었다면 상상할 수 없을 정도로 힘들었을 거예요
How would you do that in a reliable way, using just engineering code.
어떻게 믿을만한 방법으로 할 수 있을까요? 엔지니어링 코드를 이용해서요
And it's the kind of problem that's so perfect for frontier models, because that kind of nuanced understanding
개척자 모델에 딱 맞는 문제입니다. 그런 미묘한 차이를 이해하고 어떤 것에 이르는 건 가격이라는
and being able to realize that up to something means a price and that, but up to something off is not
걸 깨달을 수 있으니까요. 하지만 어떤 것에 이르는 것과 무언가를 잃는 건 가격이 아니에요.
That kind of logic is really hard.
그런 논리는 정말 어려워요
But frontier models are remarkably effective at understanding that, understanding the meaning behind
하지만 개척자 모델은 그걸 아주 효과적으로 이해하고 이런 표정의
these expressions and using that intelligently to give us an output.
의미를 이해해서 지능적으로 결과물을 만들어내죠
So just based on these prompts, we're able to now say, okay, let's get recommendations.
이 프롬프트들을 기반으로 이렇게 말할 수 있죠 get 추천을 불러와
And now we're going to see a different API than usual because we're using structured output.
이제 다른 API를 보게 될 겁니다 구조화된 출력을 사용하고 있으니까요
So my function get recommendations completion is OpenAI.
추천서 get 완료 함수는 OpenAI예요
And look it's a bit different here.
비트가 좀 다르죠?
The this is at least as of this moment uh is a beta offering from OpenAI.
적어도 지금 이 순간만큼은 오픈라이의 베타 제공이죠
But I imagine it's going to be fully productionized very, very soon.
하지만 곧 완전히 생산될 거예요
So you say OpenAI beta or that's beta for Americans.
오픈나이 베타라고 하나요? 미국에선 베타죠
Uh, OpenAI beta, dot chat, dot completions, dot parse.
오픈아이 베타, 닷챗 닷 완성, 닷 파세예요
Uh, that's the, the the way that you call this, um, and you provide the model as, as usual.
그렇게 부르는 게 맞겠죠 그리고 평소처럼 모델을 제공해요
And this is supported by GPT four and mini and GPT four, the frontier version two.
이것은 GPT4와 미니, 프런티어 버전 2 GPT4가 지원하죠
Uh, as always, the message is, you know, I'm just going to not even say it.
늘 그렇듯 메시지는 그냥 말하지도 않을 거예요
You know it.
잘 아시네요
You don't need me to tell you.
말 안 해도 알잖아요
Surely, uh, this is the difference.
이게 차이점이에요
You remember, in the past, we've used this response format as a way of specifying that we require
과거엔 이 응답 형식을 JSON이 돌아오길 요구하는 방법으로
JSON to come back.
사용했었죠
Now, this time we don't say JSON.
이번엔 JSON이라고 안 해요
What we do is we pass in the class the deal selection class.
우리가 하는 일은 거래 선택반이라는 반에서 통과시키는 거예요
That's the class we were just looking at here, the one that I did some scrappy JSON for.
방금 살펴본 클래스가 그거예요 스크래피 JSON을 했던 거죠
We pass in that class in as our response format.
응답 포맷으로 그 클래스를 넘겨요
And then when we're getting the results we don't call our usual API calls.
결과를 얻을 때 일반적인 API 호출을 하지 않아요
We say completion is zero as usual dot message and then not content but instead dot parsed.
완료는 보통 0이라고 하죠 .Mession이요 그리고 content가 아니라 .파싱이라고 해요
And that is going to take the response and parse it into an instance of deal selection.
응답을 취해 딜 선택 인스턴스로 구문 분석을 하죠
And that is what it will return.
그렇게 돌아올 거예요
So with that build up it better return it.
빌드 업을 한 후 반환하는 게 좋아요
Let's run that code and see what happens and what we get back.
코드를 실행해 어떻게 되는지 get get이 뭔지 보죠
So we are calling GPT for zero and we're sorry GPT for mini.
GPT는 0으로 호출하고 미니도 GPT로 호출할게요
We are specifying a particular structured format of output.
특정 구조의 출력 형식을 지정하고 있어요
It has returned.
돌아왔군요
Let's see why don't we print what type of thing has come back type results.
어떤 유형이 돌아왔는지 프린트해 볼까요? 유형 결과요
Let's see what kind of object has come back.
어떤 객체가 돌아왔는지 보죠
It is an agents deals deal selection.
에이전트가 거래 상대를 고르는 거예요
That is indeed the kind of object that we were hoping to get back.
Get up! Get up! Get up! 바로 저런 게 우리가 되찾고 싶었던 객체죠
I think we better, uh, see what it actually looks like.
실제로 어떻게 생겼는지 보는 게 좋겠어요
It's going to be a set.
세트로 만들 거예요
Uh, it's a deal selection which has within it deals is the one field.
거래 선택에 한 가지 분야가 포함돼 있어요
If you remember.
기억하신다면요
Deals is the one thing we set.
거래는 우리가 정한 거예요
And here are the deals.
이렇게 하죠
So let's let's find out how many deals we got back.
그럼 거래를 얼마나 따냈는지 알아보죠
We are hoping of course, that we got back five deals.
다섯 건의 거래를 성사시켰으면 좋겠어요
Let's see.
어디 보죠
We did indeed get back five deals.
정말 다섯 건의 거래를 성사시켰어요 Get it
And let's print the first of those deals.
그 거래 중 첫 번째를 인쇄하죠
And we get a Samsung Galaxy Watch Ultra, a top tier smartwatch.
그리고 탑클래스 스마트워치 삼성 갤럭시 워치 울트라를 구입했어요.
Uh, and we've got a nice summary of this.
요약본을 준비해 봤어요
And you'll notice this is actually looking it's looking great for us.
보다시피 아주 잘 되고 있어요
It's looking like this is the kind of summary that we're going to want to use when we pass it into our
요약본처럼 보이네요 가격을 입력해서 가격을
prices to estimate the price of this, and GPT four mini has pulled out a price and a URL.
추정할 때 사용할 수 있겠어요 GPT for 미니가 가격과 URL을 꺼냈네요
And of course, if we click on that URL, it's going to open up that deal.
물론 그 URL을 클릭하면 그 거래가 열리죠
There it is.
저기 있네요
Wonderful.
좋아요
Uh, so it is working well for us.
그래서 잘 되고 있어요
Uh, okay.
네
Now, the last thing to show here is that, um, we are going to, uh, look to import our scanner agent.
마지막으로 보여드릴 것은 스캐너 에이전트를 가져올 건데요
So I'm going to do the thing again where I'm going to kick this off because it's going to take a minute
다시 한 번 해볼게요. 1-2분 정도 걸릴 것 같아요.
Um, and while it's running, I'm going to go over and show you what the scanner agent is.
실행되는 동안 스캐너 에이전트가 뭔지 보여드릴게요
So the scanner agent is over here.
스캐너 에이전트는 여기 있어요
Uh, this is a bunch of code that's going to look very similar to the code that we looked at before.
이건 코드 뭉치인데 전에 봤던 코드와 아주 비슷할 거예요
Uh, and so it's, uh, just been written now with comments and with better structure so that this is
방금 작성한 건데 논평도 있고 구조도 더 나아져서 생산 품질로
something we can consider to be production quality.
평가할 수 있어요
see.
보세요
Um, but it has the system prompts that we just looked at.
하지만 방금 본 프롬프트가 있어요
It has a user prompt that we looked at and it says respond strictly with five deals, no more.
우리가 살펴본 사용자 프롬프트가 있는데 5건의 거래로 응답하라고 하네요
And what we get is an init method that sets it up and connects to OpenAI.
그러면 init 메서드를 설정하고 OpenAI에 연결할 수 있죠
The fetch deals is the method that we were just looking at that does, uh, gets a list of scraped deal
페치 거래는 방금 살펴본 방법인데 긁힌 거래 목록을 얻어요 긁힌 거래
by calling scrape deal fetch, just as you would expect.
페치라고 부르면 예상대로죠
What it also does here, though, is that potentially it gets a memory object, which is a list of URLs,
여기서 하는 또 다른 일은 잠재적으로 메모리 객체를 갖는 겁니다 URL의
and it will remove from the results anything that it remembers has already been surfaced in a previous
목록이죠 기억되는 건 이전 검색에서 이미 나타났어요
And this is how we make sure that we fetch new deals, not deals that we've already looked at before.
그래야 새로운 거래를 성사시킬 수 있어요 이미 검토한 거래가 아니라요
And of course, memory, which is one of the of the facets of building an agent framework, is something
물론 메모리는 에이전트 프레임워크를 구축하는 한 측면인데 미래에
we'll be looking at more in the future.
더 주목할 부분이죠
Uh, and then we make user prompt and then we do, uh, this is the same code as before.
사용자 프롬프트를 만들고 나서 전에 했던 것과 같은 코드를 만들고요
And then scan is basically exactly the function that we just looked at.
스캔은 우리가 방금 본 바로 그 함수예요
We make a user prompt and then we call OpenAI beta dot chat, dot completions, dot parse.
사용자 프롬프트에서 OpenAI 베타.챗 .완료 .파스를 호출해요
We pass in the model.
모델을 통과시키죠
We specify that the response format needs to be the deal selection class, so that we know that it's
응답 형식이 딜 선택 클래스여야 한다고 지정합니다 그걸 반환할 것을
going to return that and we parse it back into result.
알고 결과로 구문 분석을 할 수 있도록요
And that is what we get to right here.
Get it가 바로 여기죠
When we then, um, uh, we do first remove any deals.
그때 가장 먼저 계약을 파기해요
If the price isn't greater than zero, we don't want to return deals which have zero price.
가격이 0보다 크지 않으면 0달러짜리 거래를 반환하고 싶지 않아요
Um, and we return that result.
그 결과를 반환하죠
And if we got no deals back, um, because perhaps we'd already surfaced everything, then we return
만약 거래를 못 따내면... 이미 모든 걸 드러냈을 수도 있으니까요 그럼 하나도 못
none.
따내요
And that's indicated by that optional at the top there.
상단에 선택 사항이 있는 게 그걸 나타내죠
So that's the class.
그게 수업 내용이에요
And with that, let me go back to day three.
그럼 3일 차 얘기를 해 보죠
And we should see that the results have come back.
결과가 어떻게 나올지 봐야죠
Now one of the things I'm aware of that you may have caught, you may have noticed this yourself when
제가 알고 있는 것 중 하나는 제가 이걸 할 때 눈치챘을
I was doing this, but I was busy thinking about this while I was talking is that I think we might have
수도 있지만 저는 얘기하면서 생각을 하느라 바빴어요
just seen a goof from the model that the price here it's saying, is $350 associated with this Samsung
모델에서 실수를 본 것 같아요 가격이 350달러라고 되어 있네요 삼성 갤럭시 워치와 관련해서요
But I think when this website came up, let's close this down that it says up to 350 off with trade
하지만 이 웹사이트가 나왔을 때∙∙∙ 이걸 닫죠 트레이드 인과 함께 350까지 오퍼라고 돼 있어요
in.
다른 장치가 있으면 350까지 저축할 수 있어요
So after I showed off about how frontier models are so incredibly good at this stuff, this is an example
프론티어 모델이 이런 걸 얼마나 잘하는지 보여드렸더니 모델이 실제로
of a mistake that the model has actually made, that it thinks that this is worth 350, when in fact
저지른 실수의 예가 이런 겁니다 350달러라고 생각하는데 사실은 350달러나
it's $350 off.
싸요
So I should eat my words.
내가 한 말 취소할게요
And it did actually get that wrong.
Get it은 사실 잘못됐어요
And it's going to be interesting.
재미있을 거예요
That is, it's useful to have learned that and to have seen that.
그런 걸 배우고 목격해서 유용하죠
And I might try adding that in to the system prompt and see if we can improve on the performance of
시스템 프롬프트에 추가해 성능을 향상시킬 수 있는지 볼게요
that.
이제 그런 실수가 가능하다는 걸 알게 됐죠
Anyway, I will see you next time for the slides.
그럼 슬라이드는 다음에 보도록 하죠